A Guide to the Shepherd Family Papers, 1852-1880
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Shepherd Family Papers, 1852-1880
Library of Virginia
21358
3 leaves and 26 pages
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of J. L. Ficklen, Newport News, Virginia, 20 November 1937.
Biographical Information
Sallie E. Shepherd (1820-1904) was the daughter of John Noble (1785-1855) and Frances Fleming Payne Noble (1787-1855) of Danville, Virginia. She married William E. Shepherd (d. 1876). They are both buried in the Old Grove Street Cemetery in Danville.
Scope and Content
Papers, 1852-1880, of the Shepherd family of Pittsylvania County, Virginia, consisting of deeds for property in Pittsylvania County and for property in in Keokuk, Lee County, Iowa; two checks for the purchase of property in Pittsylvania County by Ficklen from William E. Shepherd, trustee of Sallie E. Shepherd; legal opinion of George W. Read regarding the will of John Noble (1785-1855) of Danville, Virginia, and the purchase by Ficklen; letter, 3 November 1880, concerning Sarah A. Ficklen's right to land; and miscellaneous notes.
Arrangement
Arranged chronologically.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Related Material
John Noble, Will, 18 June 1855. Accession 21357. Personal papers collection, The Library of Virginia, Richmond, Virginia.
Contents List
- Deed, 16 February 1852, for 6 acres in Pittsylvania County, Virginia, from George E. Welsh and Elizabeth Welsh to John W. McKinsey. Deed recorded in Pittsylvania County Court 12 April 1852., 4 p.
- Deed, 10 October 1854, for 12 acres and 12 poles in Pittsylvania County from Charles M. Cosby and Ann M. Cosby, of Danville, Virginia, to John W. McKinsey of Pittsylvania County. Deed recorded in Pittsylvania County Court 20 November 1854., 5 p.
- Deed, 4 May 1858, for lot numbers 11 and 12 in block 36 in city of Keokuk, Lee County, Iowa, from George C. Anderson to James E. Bruce, William O. Daniels, and Sarah J. Daniels. Deed recorded 4 May 1858 in Lee County., 2 p..
- Deed, 4 May 1858, for lot numbers 11 and 12 in block 36 in city of Keokuk, Lee County, Iowa, from James E. Bruce and William O. Daniels to Thomas Fletcher. Deed recorded 4 May 1858 in Lee County., 2 p.
- Deed, 19 May 1860, for 20 acres in Pittsylvania County from John W. McKinsey to William E. Shepherd, trustee for Sallie E. Shepherd. Recorded in Pittsylvania County 18 February 1861., 4 p.
- Check, 7 December 1862, for $10,435.07 from John F. Ficklen to William E. Shepherd, trustee of Sallie E. Shepherd for property near Danville., 2 p.
- Check, 8 December 1862, for 2064.93 from John F. Ficklen to William E. Shepherd, trustee of Sallie E. Shepherd for property near Danville., 2 p.
- Opinion, 28 February 1863, of George W. Read concerning provisions in John Noble's will relating to a purchase of land by John F. Ficklen from William E. Shepherd, trustee of Sallie E. Shepherd, Noble's daughter, with concurrence by William M. Treadway. Read reiterated his opinion in a note., 1 leaf and 2 p.
- Letter, 3 November 1880, from Harrison[?] Robertson of Danville to Sarah A. Ficklen concerning her right to the property purchased by John F. Ficklen from William E. Shepherd., 2 p.
- Notes, n.d., referring to deeds of sale of property to and William E. Shepherd in 1863 and 1864., 1 leaf.
- Wrapper, n.d., for deeds., 1 leaf.
- Wrapper, n.d., for deeds., 1 leaf.